Turning Your MISTAKES Into LESSONS I TB Joshua
Emmanuel! ! !
God is with us - Matthew 1:23
Halleluyah! ! !
Amen!! (Applause)
We have seen the name, Jesus working in the Spirit.
We have seen the value of the name.
We have seen the value of staying in faith.
Glory be to God.
Amen! ! !
Maybe many of us we don't know,
the name Jesus we call -
just as we call the name of person.
You have seen the value of the name so much
and the value of staying in faith.
Congratulations!
Applause! ! !
I'm in the midst of successful people!
Amen! ! !
Applause! ! !
I'm in the midst of joyful people!
Amen! ! !
Applause! ! !
I'm in the midst of healed people,
Amen! ! !
Applause! ! !
delivered people (Amen), blessed people! (Amen)
I know you'll like to hear that
When the Holy Spirit speaks,
changes are beginning.
Whether you like it or not, changes are beginning.
I want to say to you - you will not remain and you will not go the same.
Amen! ! !
Applause! ! !
Because we are still standing on His Word.
His Word says, "Let there be light!"
That is the promise of His Word.
Are you sick?
Let the sick come.
We are still standing on His Word
and His assurance of salvation.
Let us raise up on our feet.
Jesus has given so much capacity to learn from our mistakes, our errors.
That is why you are here today.
If there was no capacity to learn from your errors, you would not be here today.
There are some errors you committed that would have lead to death.
Many errors that you committed in the past that would have lead to death,
by now they would be pointing to your graveyard.
Many that are in the graveyard, they have never done so much that you have done.
When you think back, many that are in the graveyard today.
Many of them they have not committed the error, mistake you have committed.
but today they are pointing to the graveyard,
their dream crushed.
These are the testimonies you are supposed to be giving -
so much capacity to learn from our mistakes,
our errors and move on.
That is why you are here.
You have done so much that would have lead to graveyard,
that would have lead to death, or sick-bed,
but here you are! ! !
God has given us so much capacity to learn from our errors, mistakes.
Bow down your head now and ask God to give you enough grace to learn from your errors,
mistakes and move on.
Mistakes will come; you will learn
and not fail and move on.
Bow down your head.
Ask God to give you enough grace to continue to learn from your errors, mistakes.
Ask God for grace. He has given you but He can still increase that capacity.
There is no limit to the grace of God.
What you have today can be increased, can be multiplied; that is why you are here.
Ask God! Grace, Lord!
GRACE! ! ! GRACE! ! !
Enough grace to learn from my error, mistake.
In Jesus Christ's name we pray.
Amen!!!
Mistakes will come so far as you are still living
- in the flesh
and you will learn and move on.
So, each time that mistake comes, it is not the mistake that matters,
but what you learn from it.
You say "Why, why this mistakes" - never you say that when it comes.
You can count how many tests, examinations you've gone through,
each time you need promotion,
you should be ready for examination.
After passing the examination you'll be promoted.
Mistakes will come, don't bother yourself - why this mistakes, error, oh my God I am a christian,
why all this. No, no, no - it will come.
What if God allowed it???
If the tempter has consulted God,
"Allow me to test this man".
If God allows it?
What will you do???
Issue of why all this, "I failed this examination. Oh my God, I am a Christian," - don't let that affect your faith.
It is time to apply your faith.
Not to bother.
Mistakes will come.
Tell your neighbour.
I mean, errors will come.
You will learn and move on.
There's capacity.
There's ability.
He never promised to keep you away.
He never promised to keep you away from mistakes
because he has given you capacity.
He has given you grace.
No mistake, no grace.
He never promised to keep you away from all these - challenges, temptation, whatever
but He promised to see you through.
If gold must be gold, If gold must be gold...
If you must be a Christian...
You are to answer that.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbor again! ! !
If gold must be gold,
if you must be a Christian...
You should answer that question.
What takes gold to be gold is
what takes you to be a Christian.
If gold must be gold,
it must pass through furnace.
If you must be a Christian,
you must pass through temptations and trials.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Those things that you would have smiled when it come! ! !
"Ahh!! Why this trouble?"
Promotion is coming; get ready to pass through it.
You are now complaining.
To get ready to be promoted to G.M., you must also be ready to go through some test.
To see whether you will be qualified to be G.M.
If gold must be gold,
it must pass through furnace.
If you must be a faithful Christian, your character must be tested through rare situations.
Your test may be different from my test.
Yours may be sickness! ! !
Mr. B may be hardship.
Mr. C may be accusation.
Mr. D maybe affliction.
E - maybe limitation in progress.
There some messages you don't need to sit down and receive,
threy are many messages you must have to stand and receive; that is why you are standing.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I need your body, soul, spirit attention.
Take this:
what takes gold to be gold also
takes you to be a true believer.
Each challenge either moves you forwards or backwards.
When the Holy Spirit speaks, changes are beginning.
That is Holy Spirit.
A man has the ability to speak but the Holy Spirit speaks
and when He speaks, changes are beginning.
You must identify, who speaks to you.
A man will walk towards you and speak to you,
and, a man will walk towards you and the Holy Spirit will speak to you through him.
Who is speaking?
Anyone can say, "Jesus is Lord" but not everyone can say it genuinely.
Anyone can say, "Be healed in the name of Jesus!",
"Be delivered!", anybody can say, "Be blessed in the name of Jesus!"
Anyone can say, "Rise up and pray!" If i give you the mic now, you will say it.
To make a change, you must stand on His Word and on the assurance of salvation.
By salvation you can be healed,
because that salvation will help to maintain the healing.
If you receive without salvation, you cannot maintain it.
As you receive, it's gone.
You can be healed by salvation.
Nothing goes for nothing and nothing comes by chance.
Salvation!! Have healing, blessing, breakthrough.
You may be seated. Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You have a role to play; the prayer is not just one-sided.
As you are sitting, continue to meditate; your meditation brings results.
With your heart, you see Jesus; with your heart, you walk with Him.
You agree with Him with your heart.
And you must take control of your heart,
because our heart is just like this.
As you are sitting down if you don't take hold of your heart, as I am talking your heart will be telling you;
"Who is this man?Look at him.@
You must take hold!!! Arrest your heart.
It's not too late now, as I am talking to you. Your heart - let it look, where you look.
Begin to say, "Take more of me, give me more of You".
Begin to engage your heart.
If you don't engage your heart as you are looking at me,
you will be looking one direction and your heart will be saying nonsense.
When you greet a person, "Good Morning, sir",
your heart will be saying, "See him, very proud man. I said 'good morning', and he refused to answer me".
You will greet, your heart will not greet.
We Christians, we take hold of our hearts in order to have accomplishments, results.
What you say "Be healed!" - your heart must also release that word.
Not you are saying, your heart releases it.
As you are looking at me now, begin to meditate in your heart , don't allow your heart to be silent.
Because we Christians, we are not walking by sight, we walk by ---- (Faith)
Do you know what the Bible calls faith? What is faith?
When you say you walk by faith, you mean you walk by heart.
If you are just going by your eyes, you will always have errors all the time.
But when you walk, you must walk by your heart.
The eyes of your heart must lead you.
As I am looking now; I am not only going by what I am seeing, but this heart is the one leading me.
The heart has eyes.
The Bible says, faith is of man's heart, meaning man's spirit.
So when you are sitting, you must also sit by your heart.
Anything that is not from your heart is a sin.
Your heart and your mouth must be in accord, in agreement.
If not, we would not be able to place you.
With our mouth we confess; with our heart we believe.
Salvation!!
This is the life you must begin to live.
Are you engaging your heart now?
"Take more of me, give me more of You."
If someone is even calling you, he must call all of you.
You are two natures in one person.
You and your divine.
"Take more of me, give me more of You."
This is a prayer we anointed for you.
You may have your own prayer, no doubt about that but because of your weakness,
the Lord gave us a word that is easy for you to communicate.
"Take more of me, give me more of You, Lord!"
"Your faithfulness, Your kindness, Your purity, Your holiness."
It's simply, just simple to communicate.
Begin to say that, engage your heart.
When you now engage your heart, you begin to have fulfillment, results.
We are like this because our heart, spirit is saying this,
your eyes are saing this.
You are seeing white and your heart is talking of a different thing.
You are greeting me, "Good Morning, Sir!",
and I say, "Thank you".
Your heart at the same time will say, "Why are you greeting Him?"
You will ask yourself, "Why I am greeting this man?
Well I will greet him, he is my Pastor."
That is our heart for you.
Your heart is always not agreeing, not in accordance with whatever you do.
So, arrest your heart.
Once you are able to get this, you begin to walk in line with God.
As I am talking to you, I am also at the same time praying.
How is it possible for a man to be preaching and at the same time praying?
Yes, it's possible because I have two natures.
Two person's in one person.
It's possible.
Until you begin to live this kind of life you will overcome this world,
If not - a situation, where you say: "At 3pm I am going to pray", -
you can never overcome this world.
Tomorrow I will fast - fasting must be everyday.
The word "fasting" is abstaining from unrighteousness.
24/7 prayer.
Not when you enter the room you say, "I want to pray, I want to fast."
These are the areas satan is used to get you,
he knows, when you are not praying - he catches you.
Before you pray he catches you.
He knows, when you pray - he will not be able to catch you.
He will make sure he catches you before you pray.
Are you with me?
Are you communicating in the spirit?
That is what we call spirit prayer.
If a man is a Christian you will know. He doesn't talk too much,
because you are the only person talking.
If there is another talk in the spirit, you can't talk too much,
you will wait for the One that talks underneath.
You are calling me, "Hello, Sir", I will say "Hello, what do you want?" - I will wait for you.
I will never talk like that.
I will say, "Hello!" I will pause. You thin,k I don't hear what you are saying - I am praying underneath.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
People say eloquent speech, "Hello, Jesus is Lord", because he is the only person talking.
"Jesus is Lord!" At what time do you wait for the Holy Spirit to talk?
The One that controls you? Nobody controls you; you are the one talking.
You want to display the skill, what about the One that gives you the word?
Why can't you pause, hear from Him and say what He wants you to say?
So when you pick a phone, "Oh hello, sir!"
I am ready. I must hear from the One, my Controller what to say.
I must hear from my Commander what to say.
I must hear from my Instructor what to say.
"Hello, sir, hello! I'll just say, let me greet you." - "Thank you!"
At the same time, I am praying in the spirit.
"Can you hear me, sir?" - "I hear you quite alright."
You think, I don't hear you. I hear you, because I am not alone.
If I am not alone, I must hear from Him who sent me.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You cannot continue serving God with physical strength, eloquent speech, your eyes or mouth.
You must serve Him with all your heart.
The first place we must grow or prosper is in our spiritual life.
Let me share with you why it's so difficult for us,
after you have made a lot of money, you are rich, fleet of cars, companies, you have a lot -
yet there is a burden. Why?
Because
it's like we are prospering in our financial life, material life and everything - but in our spiritual life we are zero.
You have money, wealth so much, you have people, yet there is so much burden.
Hardly you will be able to sleep, but you are not sick.
You need help of drugs, tablets to sleep.
You cannot seat down any longer alone for 3 to 4 hours, you need to be in the midst of people to be happy.
Created joy, joy that is created - not the joy of the Lord.
So, people will make you happy, you need go to party, club house, occasion, medical checkup,
you need to go for holiday every week just to be happy.
You are just looking for joy, the one you have is not sustaining you.
Now reverse is the case; our spiritual life first!!
Because this spiritual life is the one that carries everything we have.
It carries our money, property, fame it is the spiritual life that carries it.
If something that carries you is very small, the weight will be too much for him.
The life many of us live is like you as a person carries this.
If you carry this, you will soon get tired.
Your spiritual life is like that.
What carries you is your spiritual life.
It's not your money, material, fame, popularity that carries you, wealth - no!!
What carries you, is your spiritual life.
And what you have is so much for your spiritual life to carry.
So your spiritual life is just...
That is why life is so difficult for many of us, with your money, property.
You keep asking yourself, "I have money why should I be suffering,
I have fame, companies all over the world. Why should I be suffering?"
Yes; because the person that is carrying you is carrying so much load, property
and he is the one who is supposed to be a giant and those thing are supposed to be small.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I want you to work on that.
God has given us a capacity to learn from our challenges.
So, if you don't want challenges, you don't want to learn.
Tell your neighbour.
You don't want challenges, you don't want to learn.
Tell your neighbour again.
What lesson will you learn from breakthrough?
What lesson will you learn from pleasure?
We learn much from challenges.
Your challenges could be sickness, poverty or temptation.
You don't want challenges, you don't want to learn.
You don't want to learn, you don't want to move forward.
Challenges will come; you will learn and move on.
You know the process of a seed growing.
When you plant seeds, you water them, you nurture them.
Why should you water seeds? Because of seasons - the dry season and rainy season.
You nurture them, you keep them away from insects, birds.
You try to remove weeds around it.
These are the challenges seeds have, before they grow and become beneficial to you.
In the same vein, you are a seed growing.
If your faith is lifted up, let me see your hand.
I would like to ask you a question before I leave you.
And I want somebody
from the heart
to answer this question.
How does this message appeal to you?
Don't rely on yourself but on the Holy Spirit
because the burden will arrive, challenges will come.
If you rely on yourself, you will not hold it, stand it or maintain it.
But with the Holy Spirit you will go forward.
You need challenges to learn and to move forward.
What are the challenges we are talking about?
Problems of life.
Thank you!!!
Clap for her!!
You listen to that?
She said we need challenges.
There are some challenges you cause by yourself.
When you cause a challenge and it comes, God will withdraw His strength for you to face it.
You decide to look for sugar, eat ice cream, eat sugar,
and you say you like the food.
What will you expect? (Diabetes)
And when it comes, you will face it on your own.
God will withdraw His strength from you to face the diabetes.
Without God, you will be defeated, destroyed, you will die.
Emmanuel!!! (God with us)
I have learnt today from our Senior Prophet TB Joshua that
being a human being we must pass through some challenges
because before gold must be gold it must pass through fire.
So, before a Christian is a real true born again Christian, he must pass through some challenges.
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Brother, can you just give us more, what challenges are you going through now?
The challenges can be sickness... --- I say, you.
Just tell us one of the challenges because everyone here has 1,2 or 3.
Family Challenges!!
That is disunity,
so that is it which is common.
The question now is: if you are not the cause -
because some of us this issue of family we are the cause.
We cause it and when we cause it, in that sense God withdraws His power and leaves us to face it.
So, thank you, brother, thank you very much!!
God bless you!!!
Applause